People should not be afraid of their governments.
Governments should be afraid of their people.
V for Vendetta is a action, thriller, science
fiction film directed by James McTeigue.
In a world in which Great Britain has become a fascist state, a masked vigilante known only
as “V” conducts guerrilla warfare against the oppressive British government.
When V rescues a young woman from the secret police, he finds in her an ally
with whom he can continue his fight to free the people of Britain.
Evey, played by Natalie Portman.
V / William Rookwood, played by Hugo Weaving.
Finch, played by Stephen Rea.
Deitrich, played by Stephen Fry.
Adam Sutler, played by John Hurt.
Creedy, played by Tim Pigott-Smith.
V for Vendetta is a 2005 dystopian thriller film directed by James McTeigue in
his directorial debut, from a screenplay by the Wachowskis.
It is based on the 1988–89 DC Vertigo Comics limited series graphic novel of
the same name by Alan Moore, David Lloyd, and Tony Weare.
The film, set in a future where a fascist totalitarian regime has subjugated the UK, centres on V (portrayed by Hugo Weaving), an anarchist and masked freedom fighter who
attempts to ignite a revolution through elaborate terrorist acts, and Evey Hammond (portrayed by Natalie Portman), a young woman caught up in V's mission.
Stephen Rea portrays a detective leading a desperate quest to stop V.
Produced by Silver Pictures, Virtual Studios and Anarchos Productions, Inc., V
for Vendetta was originally scheduled for release by Warner Bros.
Pictures on 4 November 2005 (a day before the 400th Guy Fawkes Night), but was delayed; it instead opened in the United States on 17 March 2006, to mostly
positive reviews from critics and became a box office success, grossing $134.7 million against a production budget between $50–54 million.
Alan Moore, dissatisfied with the film adaptations of his other works, From Hell (2001) and The League of
Extraordinary Gentlemen (2003), declined to watch the film and asked to not be credited or paid royalties.
Some political groups have seen V for Vendetta as an allegory of oppression by
government; anarchists have used it to promote their beliefs.
The film is credited for popularizing the use of the Guy Fawkes mask
by anti-establishment political groups and activities.
The film explores themes of government,
detective, revolution, dystopia, fascism.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.